Bryan Stevens

<u>b.stevens.photo@gmail.com</u> github.com/bryanstevens314

I've had a love for everything tech for as long as I can remember, I realized early though that the only way to succeed in such a demanding field is by standing on the shoulders of giants and learning from the best. With that has come a simple philosophy that has pulled me through life, that if you touch something you do it to the best of your ability, period. No excuses, no run around; you do the research, you put in the hours and you deliver the best product possible.

Technical Skills

Proficient: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, React, React Native, PHP, ORMs

Knowledgeable: Java, Swift, Objective-C, Angular, Typescript, C#, SQL, Redux, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai

Experience

(2021) <u>VuSpex GO: React Native - OpenTok - Geolocation Services:</u> Developed as a cross platform, single code base solution to replace VuSpex' existing iOS & android mobile apps. The app leverages multiple technologies to allow contractors, field agents, and permit applicants to conduct virtual inspections, create field reports to send to the inspector, and schedule face-to-face or virtual inspections. https://apps.apple.com/us/app/vuspex-go/id1556156809

- (2020) <u>ELevel+: React Native React Native Bluetooth LE:</u> Developed by myself and 2 others as part of a contract; the app connects and communicates with AccuAir's bluetooth module to receive, display and update real time height and position indicators as well as a handful of diagnostic feedback. Core to the app is this ability to update the 4 pieces of AccuAir's firmware stack through a chunked OTA update process.
- (2018) <u>Stack Chat: NodeJS SocketIO React:</u> Application was built as a pair programming exercise alongside a fellow Fullstack Alumni enabling users to create accounts, establish rooms and message in real time.
- **(2016)** <u>Bitcoin Faucet: Objective-C:</u> The app utilized multiple ad networks to mediate advertisements; that coupled with persistent timestamps, small amounts of a Bitcoin were dished out to users for viewing ads. The app was live for several months with over 4.2K total downloads and over 230,000 sessions.

Work

VuSpex - Lead Software Engineer

May 2020 - Present

- Demonstrated expertise in translating client specific needs into easy to understand software solutions
- Proficiently troubleshot simple and complex technological issues across varying tech stacks
- Utilized software engineering expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle

StreamGuys - Junior Software Developer

September 2019 – May 2020

- Modified HTML, Javascript and css to optimize page performance
- Documented all supported systems to effectively train new and existing customers
- Provided prompt solutions and proactive troubleshooting to resolve subtle and complex issues

Education

Fullstack Academy of Code

October 2018 - February 2019

- Nationally-ranked software engineering bootcamp with a 9% acceptance rate
- Studied Object-Oriented Design, asynchronous programming and software design
- Extensively practiced pair-programming pairing with all other 28 students individually

Cuesta College August 2011- June 2015

• Studied Mechanical Engineering with minor study in Computer Science